The rules keep changing.
I've been rehearsing every possible outcome.
Once this thought arises, there is no more room for right or wrong.
I am resolved to sever this flood
so that my soul can break free from mediocrity,
from loneliness and distinction.
One more step and you'll fall into madness.
Don't fall down.
I look towards the top.
Chase !
Refined to perfection.
Never retreat, no matter the danger.
I dare to defy the heavens !
Always overcome the obstacles,
ignite the seas with blood,
bloom through trials and tribulations.
Even the sharpest thorns
will be reduced into ashes.
What is there to fear ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Empty space\NAllheaven Star System
Sun Xueshan\NSun Family member\NEarly stage Soul Transformation
I told you to leave that Brilliant Red Stone alone.
If this goes on,
the insects will devour us
Ran Yue\NRan Family member\NMiddle stage Soul Transformation
before the reinforcements from our families even arrive.
Throw it away right now !
Go !
I'm unfamiliar with this Allheaven Star System.
To find Planet Dong Lin,
I need to learn about this place.
Thunder Seal Bracelet,
activate !
The Dark Fog Insects are intelligent.
Even if we throw away the Brilliant Red Stone now,
they'll still hunt us down !
These Dark Fog Insects fear thunder spells the most.
If we can hold on with the Thunder Seal Bracelet for a few days,
a Senior skilled in thunder spells will surely come to rescue us !
Such a powerful thunder spell !
I'm a member of the Ran Family !
If Senior can rescue us,
Planet Ran Yun
will repay Senior generously !
Planet Ran Yun ?
Planet Ran Yun is only 7 days of travel from here.
If Senior wishes to go,
we Juniors can lead the way !
They're all at Soul Transformation
but they show all their expressions
without concealing anything ?
They really are silkpants...
Note: silkpants = spoiled kids
Junior
is of the Ran Family's 9th generation.
Senior,
are you a Thunder Celestial Messenger ?
Planet Ran Yun is governed by our Ran Family,
the Sun Family, and the Zhao Family.
If Senior wishes to go to Planet Ran Yun,
we Juniors can lead the way there.
Thunder Celestial Messenger...
It seems that in the Allheaven Star System,
this status is extraordinary.
Are there other planets
around Planet Ran Yun ?
Senior,
Planet Ran Yun is affiliated with Planet Thousand Illusions,
one of the 5 main planets of the Northern Domain.
There are dozens of other affiliated planets
like Planet Ran Yun.
Planet Thousand Illusions ?
We will always remember
that Senior saved us.
However...
We still don't know Senior's esteemed name.
Xu Mu
Xu Mu ?
From the Xu Family of Planet Thousand Illusions ?
Or maybe...
the Xu Family from Planet Wu You ?
Where does Senior come from ?
Junior
shouldn't have asked recklessly.
My tongue slipped.
Please forgive me, Senior.
Do you know where Planet Dong Lin is ?
Dong Lin !?
The legendary Slaughter Planet !
Dong Lin
is the number one planet of the Eastern Domain of Allheaven.
We only know its whereabouts are unpredictable.
Sometimes it's there
and sometimes it's not.
This planet
in the Allheaven Star System
is known as Slaughter Planet Dong Lin.
It's...
renowned.
Continue to lead the way.
I must report this immediately.
This person
is too dangerous.
6 days later
Planet Ran Yun
Senior,
we've arrived at Planet Ran Yun.
We Juniors must return to our families immediately to report
and cannot accompany you further.
Senior can make himself at home.
Slaughter Planet Dong Lin...
Going there with my current cultivation
is probably way too dangerous.
To find a glimmer of hope for Wan'er,
I must breakthrough as soon as possible
and reach the second step.
Ran Yun City\NPlanet Ran Yun
If I use restrictions to conceal my appearance,
Xu Mu\NWang Lin's disguise\NLate Stage Core Formation
even those familiar with me will find it hard to recognize me.
One Middle stage Ascendant,
Ran Xuefeng\NRan Family Ancestor\NMiddle stage Ascendant
two Early stage Ascendants.
Sun Xi\NSun Family Ancestor\NEarly stage Ascendant
they must be the Ancestors of the Ran, Sun and Zhao families.
Zhao Chuanwen (Carefree Xanren)\NZhao Family Ancestor\NEarly stage Ascendant
This planet has abundant spiritual energy
but only 3 Ascendant cultivators.
If this were the Alliance Star System,
it would've been the theater of bloody
and restless wars.
If all the affiliated planets of the Northern Domain are like this
then Allheaven
is truly prosperous...
This dense spiritual energy
makes for an excellent hiding spot.
Even if the All-Seer has heaven-defying abilities,
he would never expect
that I am hiding here
as a Core Formation.
Cultivation Hall\NSun Family
Channeling earth spiritual energy into rooms ?
Quite ingenious...
Sun Ling\NSun Family member\NMiddle stage Nascent Soul
Upper rooms
are 1000 low quality spirit stones per year.
Lower rooms, 100.
Decide quickly.
A lower room will do.
Fifth West room,
go ahead.
Looking all around when he arrived,
impatient and restless...
He clearly lacks a firm Dao Heart.
Forming his Nascent Soul
is but a daydream.
Gather spiritual energy
to transform it into warmth
and nurture the soul.
A clever design !
Alliance formations
are robust and powerful
but lack finesse.
Allheaven's formations
are very unique.
They sit on a Spirit Vein
yet it's openly rented out to rogue cultivators...
In the Alliance,
they would have been robbed long ago.
Allheaven
doesn't obey the same rules.
To breakthrough my cultivation,
I need an immense amount of celestial jades.
The Ascendants on this planet
may be no match for me
but their families are all interconnected.
To obtain celestial jades,
I need to find another way.
Fusing the teleportation spell into a sword
can make it strike enemies
a thousand li away.
Fusing a domain and Dao Comprehension into an artifact
will fetch a high price.
Although my Dao Comprehension is powerful,
it's still a modern artifact.
What really drives people crazy
is elusive things
and ancient opportunities.
An ancient inheritance is difficult to find
but a restriction that fakes one
is possible.
Unless one's mastery of restrictions far exceeds mine,
they won't see through it.
Although it's weaker than a celestial artifact,
it's still valuable
when handled properly.
Fellow cultivator.
What is it ?
Do you know where
I can sell high-quality artifacts ?
The Whole Treasure Pavilion
that belongs to the Sun Family
buys and sells artifacts.
Whole Treasure Pavilion\NRan Yun City
Whole Treasure Pavilion
Fellow cultivator, you surely know the rules of our Pavilion.
What are the rules ?
Sun Feng\NSun Family member\NEarly stage Nascent Soul
Listen well !
Our Whole Treasure Pavilion has 2 rules for entry and 1 for exit.
Those with a cultivation below Nascent Soul
can't enter.
Those without a 100 000 high-quality spirit stones
Those who enter but don't make a transaction
can't exit.
Fellow cultivator, judge for yourself
if you're qualified.
Since reaching Soul Transformation,
I have only cultivated with celestial jades.
100 000 high-quality spirit stones
isn't something I have at hand...
With your meager cultivation,
even if you were to enter,
you'd struggle to meet the condition to exit.
Go back home,
don't make a fool of yourself.
Will you accept this ?
A poorly made sword...
The blade is dull.
It has spells attached ?
But the execution is too clumsy,
it's not worth considering.
This fool treats this trash as a treasure ?
Ridiculous !
Not even a low-grade artifact.
Not accepted, not accepted.
Take it back.
Does this place
have a Soul Transformation manager ?
We do have Soul Transformation Seniors.
But you
a mere Core Formation cultivator
are unworthy of an audience.
Sun Ning\NSun Family Elder\NEarly stage Soul Transformation
Feng'er,
don't be rude to our guest.
Elder !
Why have you graced us with your presence ?
What a fine spell-infused flying sword !
It's infused with the Dao of spatial teleportation,
it could slay Celestials.
This is a pseudo-celestial artifact !
Young one,
this is a family heirloom, is it not ?
Are your family's Elders aware
that you're trying to sell it ?
3000 celestial jades
Dao Essence ?
This mirror contains Dao Essence !
With my Soul Transformation cultivation,
I can't completely see through it !
This item
is extraordinary.
This mirror...
what's your price for it ?
50 000
50 000 celestial jades !?
That would consume most of my savings...
But an artifact containing Dao Essence
is too precious...
I may never encounter such an opportunity ever again !
An ancient pseudo-celestial artifact
with an ancient inheritance !
This kind of pseudo-celestial artifact
with inheritances are exceedingly rare !
They're all legendary treasures !
If I can break this ancient restriction,
and obtain this artifact,
this would be the greatest opportunity of my life !
Young...
Young friend...
How much
do you
want to sell this artifact for ?
100 000 celestial jades !
Core Formation cultivation ?
Young friend's item
is far too precious.
Our Whole Treasure Pavilion is unworthy of accepting it.
May fate bring us together again.
He...
ressembles him too much...
Sun Tai\NWhole Treasure Pavilion manager\NEarly stage Soul Formation
This silhouette...
My eyes must be failing me.
The universe is vast...
How could it be him ?
Forget it...
Sun Tai
It's you !
Ceng Niu !
It really is you !
Such restrictions...
What's your cultivation level !?
Could it be
that you have already reached Ascendant !?
Ascendant...
The Soul Formation brat I once toyed with has actually reached Ascendant...
And I
the esteemed Head Elder of the Corpse Sect
have ended up
in such a state...
The Giant Demon Clan Ancestor was only at Soul Transformation.
How could his spell
traverse star systems
and send you to Allheaven ?
This matter
has puzzled this old man for centuries...
Back then,
I was mysteriously teleported here.
Soon after,
I was captured by the Lu Family of this planet
and served as a lowly servant for 100 years.
My cultivation was crippled.
Why is the slave restriction
that I have on you so faint ?
This brand
was also erased by the Lu family.
On Planet Dong Lin,
is there a Xiang Family ?
This old man's status is too low.
As far as I know,
there is no Xiang Family.
Perhaps
I was not qualified to know such secrets.
This is old tea from the Alliance Star System.
I have been reluctant to drink it for many years.
But today,
I reunite with an old friend.
Please share a cup with this old man.
You crafted artifacts yourself to exchange for celestial jades ?
it seems
you have not been in Allheaven for long.
The Allheaven Star System is similar to the Alliance Star System.
Both are formed from fragments of the Ancient Celestial Realm.
Of the four Celestial Realms,
the Alliance corresponds to Rain
while Allheaven
corresponds to Thunder.
But the difference is that
the Thunder Celestial Realm
seems to
still be somewhat intact.
Thunder spells here are incredibly powerful.
The greatest power in Allheaven today
is the Thunder Celestial Temple.
Thank you for telling me.
Thank me for what ?
Nowadays,
I am but a Soul Formation old man with crippled cultivation.
Relying on my crafting skills,
I managed to become a manager at the Sun Family's
Whole Treasure Pavilion.
And your lifespan ?
I have less than 20 years left.
This old man can feel it.
My end
is near.
In 20 years,
if I am still on Planet Ran Yun,
I will come to see you off.
Ceng Niu,
now that you have reached Ascendant,
each step forward
will require a vast amount of celestial jades.
What you gained from those
pseudo-celestial artifacts
is but a raindrop in the ocean.
What you did today
by exposing such artifacts while appearing as a Core Formation cultivator
is too conspicuous !
The Sun Family,
and especially that old ghost Sun Ning
are not good people.
Be careful
or you will get in trouble.
Thank you.
Outside Ran Yun City\NPlanet Ran Yun
The fish has taken the bait.
Core Formation brat,
hand over the hairpin
and I'll spare your life !
I did it !
That hairpin
and the celestial jades
are all mine !
This...
How is this possible !?
He's not Core Formation !?
This man
is at least Middle stage Soul Transformation.
He still dares to attack me even if
he know I'm from the Sun Family ?
Once I return to the family members,
we will destroy him !
Sun Family's ancestral home\NPlanet Ran Yun
Elders ! Quick !
A powerful enemy is attacking me !
Notify all the Elders !
Understood !
We'll kill this villain together !
He must not escape !
Understood !
He was the one who ambushed me first
yet I am the villain ?
What a despicable rat who twists the truth.
Interesting !
Celestial jades
will be easy to obtain.
After placing down the restrictions, Wang Lin pondered a bit, recalling the cultivator back on Suzaku that had the domain of time. With his current cultivation level and due to having his own Dao, he was able to imitate it pretty well.\NWith a wave of his right hand, the bronze mirror fell and the time domain entered it.\NThen Wang Lin recalled again. This time it was Liu Mei’s Thousand Illusion Ruthless domain. Endless illusions flashed across his mind until they eventually turned into a ray of light that entered the hairpin.\N---\NSun Tai pondered for a long time before standing up. He looked out the window and softly said, “You… Can you promise me something?”\NWang Lin didn’t open his eyes and calmly said, “Speak.”\N\N“If you really send me off in 20 years, please take my ashes back to the Alliance Star System’s planet Dark Moon. There is a mountain that pierces into the sky. I remember there being a village at the foot of the mountain. Please send my ashes back there.”\NWang Lin let out a sigh, then he opened his eyes and nodded at Sun Tai.\N\NSun Tai revealed a smile of gratitude. At this moment, he was like a mortal old man who wanted to return to his roots after he died and not become a foreign ghost.\NHe took out a bag of holding, slowly put it down, and said, “Here are some celestial jades. I been saving them for the day when I recover my cultivation, but after seeing you, I feel like I don’t need them anymore. There are also records of my alchemy and artifact refining experiences. Take them as my thanks for sending his old man home.”\N\NGiving away his bag of holding was him loosening a knot in his heart. It meant that he had given up on recovering and had given up on everything, including the unwillingness he felt for the hundreds of years he had spent here.\NIt was because of Wang Lin that he ended up with such a fate, but also because of Wang Lin that he was relieved of the pain in his soul for hundreds of years. If there was karma, this was it.\N\NThe sun setted and Wang Lin closed his eyes. Life and death, karmatic cause and karmatic effect are only separated by just one thought, much like Yin and Yang, true and false.\NThis was the way the world was.
Ask
Qi Condensation
the perilous path filled with countless blades.
Foundation Establishment
Can the mundane world be shattered
Core Formation
Nascent Soul
by a child's steadfast heart ?
If the laws of this world
Soul Formation
Soul Transformation
stand in the way,
I'll defy the universe to tread the heavens
Ascendant
and ask this question to the sky.
My heart's deepest wish
is to not kneel before these mountains and rivers.
Don't accept your doomed fate,
karma can be changed.
Unwilling to let go,
my obsessions propel me forward.
Don't be afraid.
Thunder rumbles as I dare to tread through the reincarnation cycle.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.
Accept your fate and stay mortal or defy it to become immortal.
Hold fast to this resolve and break through the obstacles.
I'll fight all those who dare to stand in my way.
Let the winds of war heed my command.
I sign this question with my heart.
What is the Dao ?
Defying the flow of heaven and earth,
the heart I cultivate stays true.
I contemplate the wisdom of heaven and earth.
I shall choose my path between karma and fate.
My unshakable Dao Heart
aspires to ascend.
Defying,
this is what my journey to treading the heavens relies on.